welcome to another darktable tutorial
欢迎来到另一个暗桌教程
today we're going to learn how to use
今天我们要学习如何使用
the color mapping module which will let
色彩映射模块 它将让
us take an image this is just like a
我们拍一张照片 这就像是
JPEG image I just downloaded from
我刚刚从下载的JPEG图像
pixabay and as a certain look to it but
Pixabay和它的某种外观 但
we can use the color mapping module to
我们可以使用颜色映射模块来
kind of map similar colors in certain
在某些情况下颜色相似的地图种类
images so these are all this original
这些图片都是原创的
images for the most part they haven't
图像在很大程度上是没有的
been edited at least not in darktable
至少不是在暗表中编辑过
they probably have been edited to kind
它们很可能已经被编辑成了
of achieve this look but we don't have
但我们没有这样的造型
the history stack so if we want to kind
历史堆栈 所以如果我们想要
of replicate a certain look we can do
复制我们可以做到的某种外观
that using the color mapping module so
所以使用色彩映射模块
under more modules we just go down it's
在更多的模块下 我们只需往下走
in alphabetical order so we find color
按字母顺序排列 这样我们就可以找到颜色
mapping which is this one right here and
映射哪个是这个 就在这里
we click it and it enables it up top
我们点击它 它就会在顶部启用它
here and so now this is the color
这里 现在 就是这个颜色
mapping module and we see it's already
映射模块 我们看到它已经
I'm not sure if it's grabbing this or if
我不确定它是抓住了这个还是
this is from what I was using last time
这是我上次用过的
but if we get something maybe like this
但如果我们得到这样的东西
one we go back to the original of this
一 我们回到这件事的原点
and see what it looked like
看看它是什么样子的
we can choose to acquire a source or
我们可以选择获取信号源或
acquire a target and it's called acquire
获取一个目标 它被称为获取
but really it's putting the the colors
但实际上它是在把颜色
on to a target but when we do acquire
锁定目标 但当我们确实获得
source it'll grab whatever we're looking
来源：它可以抓取我们正在寻找的任何东西
at at this current level of history and
在目前的历史水平上
it will just acquire if we have it set
如果我们把它设置好 它就会获得
up for three it'll grab three different
最多三个 它就会抓住三个不同的
areas of colors and it hasn't like from
颜色的区域 它不喜欢来自
light to dark and so it grabbed the red
从浅到暗 所以它抓住了红色
from this car and the rims over here it
从这辆车和这边的轮缘上
grabbed some of the greens and yellows
抓住了一些绿色和黄色
from the plants and to grab some of
从植物上取下一些
these blues and grays from work from
这些工作中产生的忧郁和灰色
around to and so if we wanted to apply
如果我们想申请的话
this look to another image say maybe
这看起来像是另一幅画 也许
this image here we would just have this
这张图片我们会有这样的画面
image loaded in and then we go to
图像已加载 然后我们转到
acquire as target and what that'll do is
收购作为目标 这将会做的是
attempt to put these colors over top of
试着把这些颜色放在上面
this image so it took just a second to
这张图片花了一秒钟的时间
do that some processing but now we see
做一些处理 但现在我们看到
it's using these colors and it's finding
它正在使用这些颜色 它正在寻找
similar colors that kind of correspond
相似的颜色 那种对应的
and it's applying them so we see it
它正在应用它们 所以我们看到了它
didn't change the white at all but it
完全没有改变白色 但它
should change the look of this so if we
应该改变这件事的样子 所以如果我们
disable this we can see how it looks
禁用此功能 我们可以查看它的外观
like before and after oh I guess it did
就像之前和之后 哦 我想是的
change the white it darkened some of the
变白了 它变暗了一些
white some of the grays and the whites
一些灰色的和白色的
were darkened let's look at another
都变暗了 让我们看看另一个
example and this one I was doing early
这个例子和我之前做的这个
I did five targets so let's change it up
我做了五个目标 所以让我们改变它
again or five clusters so I set up to
再一次或五个集群 所以我设置为
five because I kind of want to get the
五个因为我有点想拿到
Blues the yellows and oranges and then
使黄色和橙色变蓝 然后
some of these dark dark grays and also
其中一些深灰色 还有
some of the light Gray's and so or the
一些浅灰色的或类似的
the shades whatever they are blues
色调 不管它们是什么蓝调
shades of blue
深浅不一的蓝色
so I'll click acquire as source and
因此 我将单击Acquire as SOURCE并
we'll see this source acquired here and
我们会在这里看到这个来源 并
then I'll go to an image that I've done
然后我会去看一张我拍过的照片
of clouds this one here which is for the
云彩 这一朵是为了
most part unaffected let's put it back
大部分不受影响 让我们把它放回去
down there and so this is just my kind
在那里 所以这只是我的同类
of more or less raw image and I'll just
或多或少的原始图像 我只想
go acquire as target and it'll probably
去收购作为目标 它很可能会
make it look pretty similar to that
让它看起来和那个很像
other picture so there we go we've see a
其他图片 所以我们开始了 我们看到了一张
lot more oranges in the skyline a lot
更多的橙子在天际线上
more purpley in the top we don't get as
更多的紫色在顶部 我们不会得到
many as much of that blue we get a lot
同样多的蓝色我们得到了很多
more purple just because of what it
更多的紫色只是因为它
interpreted this picture is having but
解读这张图片是有意义的
again we can kind of change that a
再说一次 我们可以改变
little bit kind of the shadows a little
有点阴影 有点
bit on there I guess I would say and
在那里 我想我会说
then also this color dominance just
那么 这种颜色优势也只是
makes it kind of like saturation or how
让它变得有点饱和或如何
strong the colors are and so we can
颜色很强烈 所以我们可以
leave that up there so that's not too
把它放在那里 这样就不会太
bad not as good but then again it's a
糟糕 没有那么好 但话又说回来 它是
good starting point for the colors at
颜色的良好起点是
least so it looks a lot more interesting
这样看起来就更有趣了
than it did before at least we have
比以前更多 至少我们有
those colors to work with and then we
用这些颜色来工作 然后我们
can apply modules on top of this to get
可以在此基础上应用模块以获取
the look we want so play around with
我们想要的样子 所以玩吧
that color mapping module it's a good
那个色彩映射模块 很好
tool to have and sometimes you'll just
工具 有时你只会
want to it yeah without having to go
想去吗？是的 不用去
through and and grab a certain look of
通过和 并抓住一定的外观
an image you can just very quickly you
一个你可以非常迅速地让你
know copy it acquire it as target and if
知道 复制它 作为目标获取它 如果
nothing else you can kind of analyze and
没有其他东西你可以分析和分析
see what those colors are out helps you
看看那些颜色是什么帮助你
break out and be like oh yeah that is
爆发出来 就像哦 是的 这就是
more of a yellow than a green and it can
更像是黄色而不是绿色 它可以
kind of help you interpret the colors of
能帮助你解读出
an image so a great module and I think
一个如此棒的模块的图像 我认为
I've gotten to the end of what I can
我已经尽我所能了
teach you in darktable you may have even
在暗桌上教你 你甚至可以
noticed that there's lots of resources
注意到有很多资源
you may have encountered already here on
您可能已经在这里遇到过
YouTube and all over the internet
YouTube和整个互联网
teaching how to use some of these
教授如何使用其中的一些
different modules specifically and
不同的模块 特别是
diving deeper than we've gone in this
潜入比我们在这里更深的地方
tutorial series but I think I'm going to
系列教程 但我想我会
go ahead and end this series here if you
继续并在此处结束本系列 如果您
any questions or comments leave them
任何问题或评论都会留下他们
below as I come across new techniques or
下面是我遇到的新技术或
interesting new features in darktable
暗桌中有趣的新功能
I'll go ahead and add to this series but
我将继续添加到这个系列中 但是
for now I think I'm gonna move on to
现在 我认为我将继续
another video series so thanks for
又一个视频系列 所以谢谢
watching really appreciate you sticking
看着真的很感谢你的坚持
with this tutorial hopefully you've
在本教程中 希望您已经
learned something and look forward to
学到了一些东西并期待着
catching you in some future videos
在未来的一些视频中看到你